Now that we are experts on noise, let's see what happens to the histogram of an
大家已经对噪声较为熟悉 那下面就来看一看
image when you add noise to it. For that, we are going to use a very
当在图像中加入噪声时 对其直方图的影响
simple example. We see here an image that has only three
我们来看一个非常简单的例子 这幅图像只包括三个区域
regions and then only three values. If we were to draw the histogram of this
而且只含有三种灰度值 如果画出这幅图像的直方图
image, we will see a different heights but we actually see on the three,
我们看到的高度可能各有不同 但是其实只有三个δ函数
basically, delta functions. One that stands for the black region,
一个代表黑色区域
one that stands for the gray region, and one that stands for this lighter region
一个代表灰色区域 还有一个代表这个浅色区域
and the height of these depends on the area of each one of the regions.
而不同的高度则取决于各个区域的面积
So, when we add noise, with each one of these
下面分别根据这些分布来掺入噪声
distribution, how is this histogram going to change?
那么这个直方图会如何改变呢？
It's going to change from this three delta function to something.
这三个δ函数会有所改变
let's see what happens. So, here we see three examples already.
让我们来看看具体的变化 这就是三个加入不同噪声后的例子
In the first example, we took the original image and we added Gaussian
在第一个例子中 我们在原始图像中掺入高斯噪声
noise. This the type of the probability
这就是该噪声的概率分布图
distribution of the noise. And we actually see it reflected here.
可以看到这个图也反映出这种噪声分布
It's very clearly, they are kind of three Gaussian distributions.
这是三个很清晰的高斯分布
This is going to be very important, it's going to help us to estimate the noise,
这一点将会非常重要 如果我们只有噪声污染后的图像
if we are only given the image, as we are going to see in the next video.
就像接下来的视频中那样 它能帮助我们估计噪声类型
Here, we see a shape which is very similar to the shape of their Rayleigh
这里 我们可以看到一个与瑞利噪声 非常相像的形状
noise. It's kind of tilted and then it goes down
它有些倾斜 其他部分
almost like a Gaussian, slightly different.
类似于高斯分布 但有些许不同
So clearly, the shapes here are very
很明显这两个形状是非常不同的
For example, this is kind of symmetric. This is not.
就比如说 这个比较对称 但是这个不是
Remember, these are probability distributional functions for the noise so
记住 这些只是噪声的概率分布
we are not expecting to see a perfect function.
所以我们并不指望能看到一个完全一致的函数
This all in probability. And here, we see the gamma noise.
全部都只是可能性 这个是伽马噪声
Once again, a shape very similar around each one of the pixel values,
同前面一样 在每一个像素值附近都是相似的形状
a shape that is very similar to the actual probability distribution function.
这个形状和实际的概率分布函数非常接近
So, these are the three of them. They just continue seeing some additional
这里是三个例子 我们继续来看看一些其他的例子
examples. I'm going to ask you now a question.
下面我来问大家一个问题
Which noise do you think we added here to the original image?
大家认为这张图被添加了哪一种噪声？
So, this is how the, basically, the image looks after we add the noise.
这是添加过噪声之后的图像
Which one of these six do you think we have added here?
我们在这上面添加了这六种噪声之中的哪种呢？
Please give me an answer to that. I think it's not very hard to get to the
请告诉我你的答案
answer if we just compare the shapes. Once again, remember, if we only had the
如果比较一下形状的话 应该不难得到正确的答案
original image, we have kind of three delta functions with different heights
再提醒一下 我们的原始图像 只有三个不同高度的δ函数
representing the black, the gray, and the white regions.
分别代表黑色 灰色 和白色三个区域
And now, we see very clearly, exponential functions.
我们可以看出这是非常明显的指数函数
So, it was these noise, okay? We cannot see that from the image
所以答案是这个噪声 你答对了吗？
itself. It's very hard to see.
我们无法直接从图像中看出来
Is this Gaussian, is this exponential, is this Rayleigh?
我们难以分辨这是高斯函数 指数函数 还是瑞利函数
You have to really be trained to observe that just from the image.
想要只凭图像判断 大家需要经过一些特殊的训练才行
But it's much easier from the histogram. So now, that we are really experts I'm
但是从直方图来判断则简单多了 那既然大家已经熟悉了这点
going to ask you again, what's the noise here?
我再问大家一个问题 这里添加的又是什么噪声呢？
Please give me an answer. Just think for a second, and give me an
请给我一个答案 稍微想一下吧
answer. Once again, this was the original
和前一题类似 这个是原始的直方图分布
histogram and now, we actually see kind of uniform distributions.
而在这里 我们可以看到有些均匀分布的样子
So, we see clearly that this is the noise.
所以很清楚就是这个噪声
It's basically around the area of the original histogram with the flat regions.
噪声在原始直方图周围形成了一段水平的区域
So, this is a type of noise. Now, please note that in this image, the
所以是这种噪声 请注意一下 在这张图像中
same type of noise was added all around the image.
整幅图像都添加了相同类型的噪声
Otherwise, for example, if we add Gaussian noise inside this region and
还有另外一种情况 比如在这个区域加入高斯噪声
uniform noise to everything else, we will see actually a Gaussian here and uniform
而在其他区域则加入均匀噪声 那我们将在这里看到一个高斯分布
in the other two. So, we will see combinations of these
在另外两个区域则看到均匀分布 也就是看到这些分布的组合
distributions. Finally, this is the salt and pepper.
最后 这是椒盐噪声
Salt and pepper actually is not hard, in general, to recognize from the original
一般来说 椒盐噪声并不难从原始图像中辨认
image. We see the black dots or the white dots.
我们可以看到黑点或者白点
But I also want to illustrate that in the histogram.
但是我仍然想从直方图的角度来阐述一下
The histogram stays with kind of delta functions but, of course, if there was no
这个直方图的形状依然有点像δ函数 但是
black there would be a new delta function of black,
如果该区域没有黑色的话 那将有一个新的δ函数代表黑色
or if there was black it would be a larger basically a taller delta function
或者如果那里已经有黑色 那可能产生一个更大范围 更高的δ函数
there and the same for y. So, we can see from the histograms what
白色区域也是一样 有时候我们可以从直方图中看出
actually happens sometimes. And therefore, we can use the histograms
图像的变化 所以我们能够利用直方图来
to estimate the type of noise and to estimate the parameters of the noise as
估计噪声的种类 以及噪声的参数
we're going to see in the next video. Thank you.
我们将会在下一个视频中学习到这些 谢谢